仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
翻译:  冰蓝   洗七里   glida
翻译:  吃货丁小七   猪肉白菜水饺
校对:  天降神助赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第八季 第五集
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
手机APP搜索
人人影视字幕组
一键收藏网盘资源生活大爆炸 吸血鬼日记
西部世界 谍网 超女
美剧资源应有尽有
扫码即刻关注
Zimuzu特别推荐
马上关注微信人人美剧（rrmjapp）
太好了  卡拉OK机
Great. The karaoke machine.
谢谢  米奇舅舅
Thanks, Uncle Mitch.
这是小卡的  他很喜欢它
It's Cam's, and he loves it.
他只要喝了两杯红酒
He's never more than two glasses of wine away
我们就躲不过一场即兴演唱会
from treating us all to an impromptu concert.
如果你把它弄坏  我给你一百块
It's 100 bucks if you break it.
-真的吗  -你要更多吗
- Really? - Do you want more?
谁是美国人最爱的电视妈妈角色
Who's America's favorite TV mom?
会是琼·
Could it be June...
她在1954年电视剧《反斗小宝贝[海狸搞定]》中
饰演的妈妈角色  曾被誉为最受欢迎的妈妈
克莉佛吗
Cleaver?
所以我就是海狸啦
That must make me the Beaver.
我听不大清  卢克的笑声有多大
I can't hear too well. How hard is Luke laughing?
这么好的哏别浪费在我这里
Don't waste this gold on me.
去亨德森一家的派对
Get over to the Hendersons' party,
玩玩老套社交游戏  跳跳老气哈娑舞
put your keys in a bowl, do the Hustle.
别紧张
Relax.
你不酷的父母
Your uncool parents
不会出现在你的派对上
aren't gonna hang around your party
把场面搞得很逊
and make it all lame.
当然不会啦
Of course not. Hey.
我听说有个孩子开了无大人监管的派对
I just heard a story about a kid who had an unsupervised party
结果一位客人摔断了腿
and one of the guests broke his leg
因为他从屋顶跳到蹦床上
because he jumped off the roof onto a trampoline
后来这人还告了主办人父母
and sued the parents.
对哦  我们有蹦床  也有屋顶
We have a trampoline. And a roof.
我得确定你是在开玩笑
I need to know that you're joking.
妈妈  一切都在我的掌控中
Mom, I have everything under control.
克莱尔  别这样
Claire, come on!
他是个负责任的好青年
He's a responsible young man!
对你儿子有点信心吧
Have a little faith in your son.
这些都是紧急电话
These are all the emergency numbers.
消防队  警察  毒物控制中心  国土安全部
That's Fire, Police, Poison Control, Homeland Security.
你来负责
You're in charge.
除非你碰巧有别的安排
I mean, unless you... happen to have other plans.
是啊  就假装昨晚我狂欢得太疯了吧
Yeah, let's just pretend I partied too hard last night.
你简直是派对狂
You're an animal.
-靠  -怎么了
- Dang it! - What's wrong?
这花别正了吗
Is this flower straight?
我不知道
I don't know. Oh!
万圣节恶作剧
Halloween prank!
那是去年的报复
That's payback from last year.
普里契特有债必偿
A Pritchett always pays his debts.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
佛利德曼家的泳池派对
The Friedmans' pool party.
我就是那意思
That's what I say.
这是什么  经典
What is -- Classic.
有苍蝇的冰块这整人老哏
The old fly in the plastic ice cube gag.
真搞笑
Very funny! Very --
不
No!
你在融化
You're melting!
米奇尔的造型出自《绿野仙踪》
这名坏女巫被泼了水后  说出了"我在融化"
你在融化
You're melting!
冰块是我做的  不是整人的
I did the ice cube.
现在换你湿了
Well, now you're the one who's wet.
不算是  大部分水都在地板上
Not really. Most of it's on the floor.
菲尔  你没事吧
Phil, are you okay?
我没事
I'm fine. Yeah.
如果海狸踩到水滑到了
Hey, you know what the Beaver said
你知道他会说什么吗
when he slipped in water?
-我靠[盖水坝挡水]  -我靠
- Damn it? - Damn it.
杰  作为天主教徒  我觉得这样不对
Jay, as a Catholic, I do not feel right about this.
耶稣[天啊]  玛利亚和约瑟夫
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph.
这是超完美的家庭变装主题
It's the perfect family costume.
根本讲不通  应该是乔扮耶稣宝宝
It doesn't even make sense. Joe should be the Jesus.
是的
Yeah!
乔是约[乔]瑟夫的简称
"Joe" Short for "Joseph."
杰是"杰"稣的简称
"Jay" Short for "Jaysus."
只有这样才讲得通
It's the only way it makes sense.
但他才是宝宝
But he's the child.
你想多了
You're overthinking it.
你懂我扮的是谁  对吧
Huh? You get who this is, right?
哈丽特·浴缸男[塔布曼]
Harriet Tub Man?
美国废奴主义者
作家乔伊斯·卡罗尔·漂浮[欧茨]
Oh, Joyce Carol Floats.
演员法拉·水龙头[福赛特]  开水的水...
Farrah Faucet, spelled F-A-U --
我懂你意思
Yeah, I get it.
你为什么只猜女人啊
And why are you only guessing women?
我是达尔顿·特朗勃  被列入黑名单的编剧
I'm Dalton Trumbo, blacklisted screenwriter,
1947-57年间  二战后对共产主义的恐惧与仇恨
使美国娱乐业中被认为支持共产主义者  皆上了黑名单
在浴缸里创作
wrote in a bathtub.
我有点担心去年他的传记电影出来后
I'm a little worried that because of the movie,
很多人都会弄这个打扮
a lot of people will have this costume.
我觉得没事  参加卢克派对的人
I think you're good. Nobody going to Luke's party
绝对不会弄明白你扮的是谁
will ever be able to figure out that costume.
所以我要去参加另一场派对
Yeah, that's why I'm going to a different party.
你不能为了去别人的派对而不去卢克的派对
You're not skipping Luke's party to go to someone else's.
卢克的派对上人会很多的
There's going to be a million people at Luke's.
他不会在乎我去了没
He's not going to care whether or not I attend.
曼尼  这是因为卢克战胜了你
Manny, is this because Luke beat you
成为了学生会主席吗
for class president?
你为什么忘不掉这惨绝人寰的羞辱呢
Why can't you get over this devastating humiliation?
因为总有人事物让我一直想起
Because something keeps me reminding me.
但这跟那件事无关
But it has nothing to do with that.
苏菲·钱伯斯办了一场派对
Sophie Chambers is throwing a party
参加的人成熟多了
with a much more sophisticated crow--
你不许参加奸人厄尔·钱伯斯家族里
You're not going to any party thrown by any member
任何人举办的任何派对
of that crooked Earl Chambers family.
那杂种从我眼皮下偷走了我的橱柜公司
That bastard stole my closet company right out from under me!
不不
No, no, no, no, no.
你扮成了耶稣的样子  就别说"杂种"了
Don't say the word "Bastard" when you're dressed like Jesus!
有人觉得耶稣是未婚生的孩子  所以是个...
你  决不能背叛家人
And you -- never turn your back on family.
我戈麦斯表哥没去我另一个戈麦斯表哥的派对
My cousin Gomez skipped my other cousin Gomez's party,
我戈麦斯表哥感觉背后被人捅了刀
and my cousin Gomez felt completely stabbed in the back.
-因为他...  -因为他就是被捅了
- Because he -- - Because he was.
拜托  派对会在苏菲祖父的住宅举办
Come on. The party's going to be at Sophie's grandpa's mansion.
这是本季的社交大事
It's the social event of the season.
你得去参加卢克的派对
You're going to Luke's!
凭什么啊
That's not fair!
你听到你妈说的话了  你得去参加卢克的派对
You heard your mother! You're going to Luke's!
-你去参加厄尔家的派对吧  -什么
- You're going to Earl's. - What?
但你必须往他鞋子里放死鱼
You're gonna put dead fish in his shoes.
做为交换  如果你妈起疑心  我会替你掩护
And I'm gonna cover for you if your mother gets suspicious.
我怎么把鱼夹带进去啊
Where am I going to hide fish?
你在浴缸里哎
You're in a bathtub!
-万圣节快乐  谢谢  -万圣节快乐
- Happy Halloween! Thank you. - Happy Halloween.
-他们就拿了一个  对吧  -是啊
- They just took one, right? - Yes.
我们还要分发多少糖果
How much candy do we have to hand out
我才能去讨糖果啊
before I go trick-or-treating?
我就不能拿把刀自己去吗
Can't I just take a knife and go by myself?
不行
No!
没人会惹我的
No one would mess with me.
我就说她太小  不适合看帮派主题的《西区故事》
I told you she was too young for "West Side Story."
你在干什么
Hmm. W-What are you doing?
干嘛  这是我今晚会吃的唯一一根士力架
What? It's my one and only candy bar for the night.
我不会再吃士力架了
No more Snickers.
如果你不想被人笑[听到士力架]
If you don't want to hear any more snickers
那就不要假装那是你最后一根
then don't pretend that's your last candy bar.
小卡吃了糖以后反应很大
Cam doesn't react well to candy.
所以我从来不吃  除了万圣节
Which is why I never eat it. Except on Halloween.
我承认  过去我太放纵自己了
And I admit, in years past, I may have overindulged.
他每次吃糖吃到嗨到山顶
Which leads to a crazy high
过后就会飙泪自我厌恶到谷底
followed by a tearful, self-loathing crash.
简直就是《醉乡情断》的翻版
It's a Days of Red Vines and Roses.
美国1966年电影  讲述从小酌变成酗酒
最后幸福家庭被击垮的故事
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat!
拿一颗吧
Yep, just take one.
我记得那个笑声  今年休想得逞
I know that laugh. Not this year.
放手
Drop it.
你疯了
You're crazy.
对  为正义疯狂
Yeah, crazy for justice!
你穿得像个恶棍
And just because you're dressed like a villain
不见得就要表现得像个恶棍
doesn't mean you have to act like one!
天啊  你敢相信吗
Oh, my God. Can you believe that?
对啊  一个九岁的孩子
Yes, a 9-year-old kid
想在万圣节多拿几颗糖
wanting extra candy on Halloween.
真是太"莫名其妙"了
Oh, it is baffling.
说到九岁孩子在万圣节要糖...
Speaking of 9-year-olds wanting candy on Halloween...
等等  亲爱的
Okay, just a second, honey.
小卡  抓住一个孩子的胳膊
Cam, maybe grabbing a kid's arm
真的不应该啊...
is where we draw the line.
我好像在每一本法律书上都读过
I think I read that in every single law book.
这话听着像是
This sounds like something
我们可以在人行道上边走边聊的内容
we could be talking about on the sidewalk.
稍等亲爱的  你知道吗  米奇尔
Okay, just a second, honey. You know what, Mitchell?
就是那个小混蛋每年都拿一大把糖走
That same little jerk grabs a handful of candy every year.
他是我的万圣节死敌
He's my Halloween nemesis.
这是一条社会契约
There is a social contract.
说一句"不给糖就捣蛋"  只能拿一颗糖
You say "Trick or treat," you get one piece of candy.
这契约一但瓦解  我们就离没有法制
That breaks down, we're just a hop, skip, and a jump
以破珠子和牙齿当钱的原始社会不远了
to a lawless wasteland where we use beads and teeth for money!
你刚才说才吃第一根巧克力棒对吧
That was your first candy bar, you say?
你也许应该摄入点蛋白质
You think maybe you should have a little protein
来平衡一下糖分
to balance that out?
我不需要蛋白质
I don't need any protein.
可是老天爷好像想你补充"蛋白质"呢
I feel like the universe is telling you differently.
是谁干的
Who did that?!
他朝那边跑了  经过了所有发糖的房子
He went that way! Past all the houses handing out candy!
交给我吧
I'm on it!
不  你看  他叫乔
No, see, his name is Joe.
对  可不都是小孩扮耶稣吗
Yeah, but wouldn't the child be Jesus?
这个电话我得接
I got to take this.
跟她解释我们这是在干嘛
Tell her what we're doing with this.
我老公要下地狱了
My husband is going to hell
他想拖着我们所有人一起
and he's trying to take us with him.
你好
Hello?
好吧  我到厄尔的卧室了
Okay, I'm in Earl's bedroom.
你想看我展示他的鞋吗
Do you want me to show you his shoes
这样你就能选让我塞鱼进哪一双
so you can pick which ones I shove fish into?
追随你的内心  孩子  等等  那是什么
Follow your heart, kid. Wait a minute. What's that?
什么
What?
你身后墙上那幅画
That picture on the wall behind you.
那是什么  我看看
What is that? Let me see it.
大卫·索尔在《警界双雄》里饰演哈奇
David Soul played Hutch in "Starsky and Hutch."
1975年电视剧
我的其中一个绝妙橱柜哏
Now, one of my groovier closet ideas
是个为你把滑雪板
was a hutch for your skis
锁在衣柜里处的架子
that latched onto the end of your closet.
我称之为柜"索"雪板
I called it the "Storeski End Hutch".
大卫·索尔还因此给了我签名照
David Soul gave me a signed picture.
有一天  那张照不见了
Well, one day, the picture disappears
厄尔假装自己是无辜的
and Earl plays innocent.
但其实多年来他就是真凶
But the whole time, he's had it.
真讽刺  这剧情能拍成
Ironically, this would've been
很好看的一集《警界双雄》呢
a great episode in "Starsky and Hutch."
偷那副画
Steal that picture!
可是鱼怎么办
But what about the fish?
别管鱼了
Forget the fish!
所以说
Oh, so, for no reason,
我这条红鲱鱼白拿了
I've just been carrying around this red herring?
我要那副画
I want that picture.
你想要就自己来偷
You want it, you steal it.
我还是有点自尊的
I still have some self-respect.
歌洛莉亚  你肯定不敢相信
Gloria, you won't believe this.
什么
What?
刚才克莱尔打来
That was Claire.
曼尼没去卢克的派对
Manny never showed up at Luke's party.
他们觉得他是去苏菲家的派对了
They think he went to Sophie's.
我对他真失望
So disappointed in him.
我知道  我也不想开车过去
I know, and I hate to drive over there
揪他去卢克的派对
and drag him to Luke's,
但我知道至少比试图阻止你要容易点
but I know better than to try to stop you.
虽然下他面子不太好
I feel bad about embarrassing him,
但这件事我已经跟他说清楚过
but I was very clear about this.
可能下次他就会懂你意思[拿到照片]了
Well, maybe next time he'll... get the picture.
你为什么要笑得这么诡异
Why did you just chuckle like that?
没事  胡子有点痒
Nothing. The -- The beard tickles.
来吧  我开车
Come on, I'll drive.
-给你  -抱歉我忘了带上尾巴了
- Here you go. - Sorry I forgot that, buddy.
我本来可以自己去拿的
I would have grabbed it myself,
但我们想尊重你的
but we were trying to respect
"无父母"派对
the whole "No parents" thing.
对了  如果我进你的派对找尾巴[监视]
Also, how would it look if I went into your party
感觉会很怪吧
looking for some tail?
这笑话下次还要再讲一遍  假装没听过
I'm gonna reuse that later. Act surprised.
好
Yeah.
亲爱的  里面情况如何
Hey, honey. How's it going in there?
超棒的
Huh? Oh. Awesome.
我得走了
Yeah, I got to go.
我知道你会说我是个
I know you were going to say
神经质的保护欲过度的妈妈  可是我...
that I'm being a neurotic, overly protective mom, but I --
我也看出来了  卢克有点不对劲
I saw that, too. Something's up with Luke.
你觉得他是不是搞不定
You think he's in over his head?
我得去查查他  我该去吗
I should check on him. Should I check on him?
我该去查查他
I should check on him.
你比我还疯的时候最性感
You are never sexier than when you out-crazy me.
不要让任何人发现你
Don't let anyone see you.
我已经...
I am way a...
领先你一"头"了
head of you.
我不是真的海狸  是我  你爸
Shh! I'm not a real beaver! It's me -- Dad!
你在搞什么鬼
What are you doing?
我只是想确认一切没事
I just wanted to make sure everything's okay.
卢克看起来很难过
Luke seems upset.
大家都去哪儿了
Where is everybody?
都跑去楼上了吗  我说了不准上楼
Are people upstairs? I said nobody upstairs!
楼上没人  连楼下也没人
Nobody's upstairs. Nobody's even downstairs.
这里大概也就五个人而已
They are literally like five people here.
你好啊  我最亲爱的
Hello, my dearest.
好吧  四个人  加一个罗本
Well, four, and Reuben.
我看你扮的是"世界上最美的女人"
I see your costume is The Most Beautiful Woman in the World.
闭嘴  罗本  你让一切都变得很瞎
Shut up, Reuben. You make everything terrible.
所以我们散了
And we're off.
别自作多情
Don't flatter yourself!
就因为我自己过万圣节
Just because I'm alone on Halloween
不代表我没有很多追求者
doesn't mean I don't have plenty of suitors!
上周  一个优步司机请求看我的美足呢
Last week, an Uber driver asked to see my feet!
罗本  你在听我说吗
Reuben, are you listening to me?!
罗本
Reuben!
-最后一个  -很好  因为你现在在颤抖
- One last one. - Good. 'Cause you're vibrating right now.
是气到发抖  不是糖吃多了  是愤怒
With rage -- Not sugar, rage.
你们好  打扰一下  你好
Hello. Excuse me. Hi.
你们有没有见到一个这么高的死小鬼
Have you seen a little brat about this tall
扮的是黑武士
dressed as Darth Vader?
扔鸡蛋  像这样笑
Throws eggs. Laughs like this --
自己去找  你是蝙蝠侠
Find him yourself. You're Batman.
这小孩记我仇敌名单上了
That one's on my list.
你的名单早记满了吧
I don't think there's any more room.
我去把这些苹果扔了
I'm gonna go throw away these apples
给糖果腾点位置
and make space for more candy.
小卡  你被鸡蛋砸了我也很难受
Cam, I feel terrible that you got hit with an egg,
但你把莉莉的万圣夜毁了
but you're ruining the night for Lily.
你一定要这么眦睚必报吗
Do you have to nurse every single grudge?
-我才不那样  -你在逗我吗
- I don't do that. - Are you kidding me?
你的死敌比真正的蝙蝠侠都多
You have more archenemies than the actual Batman.
想想那个帮你选围巾的女售货员
How about that sales lady who helped you with the scarf?
她暗示我的脖子是问题所在
She implied my neck was the problem.
和你共事的那个西班牙语老师呢
The Spanish teacher you've been working with?
他叫我"疯豆[西语]"
He calls me "locos frijoles"
好像我不懂那什么意思似的
like I don't know what that means.
-是"疯豆"对吗  -是的
- It's "crazy beans," right? - Yes, it is.
别忘了还有你原来合唱团的安德鲁
Oh, and don't forget about Andrew from your old choir.
他偷了我的琴键围巾  这也是
He stole my piano key scarf, which is why
我一开始要去那破围巾店的原因
I had to go into the stupid scarf store to begin with!
好吧  你知道吗
Okay, you know what?
或许我确实正义感过度了
Maybe I do have an overdeveloped sense of justice.
-谢谢你  -但如果我伴侣
- Thank you. - But maybe I wouldn't...
时常站我这边  我可能不会这样
if my partner took my side every once in a while.
我认同你时就会站你这边
I take your side when I agree with you.
那很简单  任何人都能做到
That's easy. Anybody can do that.
婚姻的意义在于  即使不认同
Marriage is about sticking up for your partner,
也要支持你的伴侣
even...when you don't agree with him.
是吗
Is it?
还记得上周午饭
Do you remember last week at lunch
他们给你送来标准薯条
when they brought you regular fries
你坚持你点的是地瓜薯条吗
and you insisted that you ordered sweet potato fries?
知道吗
Well, guess what.
你点的就是标准薯条
You ordered regular fries.
-不  我没有  -你绝对是那样
- No, I didn't. - You absolutely did.
但因为我爱你  所以我支持你
And I stuck up for you because I love you.
也因为你爱地瓜薯条
And because you love sweet potato fries.
-老爸  -怎么了
- Hey, Dad. - What?
你讨厌的孩子在那里
There's that kid you hate.
我了个万圣节啊  他在那儿
Holy Halloween. There he is.
说你呢  站住
Hey! You! Stop!
不好
No.
1966年电视剧《蝙蝠侠》的过场与追击音效
他要逃掉了
He's getting away!
臭斗篷
Stupid cape!
可怜的卢克  他肯定很心碎
Oh, poor Luke. He must be crushed.
这年头让高中派对满是人不像
It's not as easy to pack a high-school party
我们那时那么简单了  克莱尔
as it was in our day, Claire.
而且貌似孩子们邀请
Apparently, it's no longer cool
老师家长不再算酷了
for kids to invite teachers or parents.
让我好心痛
It makes my heart hurt.
大家是喜欢他的吧  不是吗
I mean, people like him, don't they?
怎么会不喜欢
Why wouldn't they?
他可是目前我们孩子中最讨人喜欢的
He's by far the most likable of all our children.
那为什么没人来他的派对
Then why didn't anybody come to his party?
因为人都去了苏菲·钱伯斯的派对
Because they're all at Sophie Chambers' party.
-谁  -卢克班上的一个孩子
- Who? - A kid in Luke's class.
我和她哥哥是脸书朋友
I'm Facebook friends with her brother
因为他过去卖我大[麻]发  假发
'cause he used to sell me wee-gs. Wigs.
他就是这么发音的  他是英国人
That's how he pronounces it. He's British.
你们怎么不说话呢
When are you guys gonna talk, huh?
卢克为了这场派对很下功夫
Luke worked so hard on this party.
他自制了服装  包揽了所有装饰
He made his own costume, did all the decorations.
他甚至还以为自己
He even thought he hid that bottle of
成功藏了瓶薄荷甜酒在床底下
Peppermint Schnapps under his bed.
就是这种事会毁了他的第一轮高三
This is the kind of thing that could ruin his first senior year.
慢着  我能帮上忙
Wait! I can help!
我们忘了我是做什么工作的吗
Are we forgetting what I do for a living? Huh?
我们记得啊
Uh, we remember.
你  假装和名人是朋友
You...pretend to be friends with celebrities.
以便你能卖  帽子
So you can sell h-- hats?
我是推销能手
I'm a promoter.
我可以去苏菲的派对上大赞卢克的派对
I can go to Sophie's and talk up Luke's party.
-一个小时后  绝对人满  -太棒了
- In an hour, it'll be packed. - Great!
与此同时  我去让派对嗨起来
While you do that, I'm gonna get the party started.
什么  不  不
What -- No, no.
有老爸在只会让派对更逊
A dad hanging around will only make that party lamer.
老爸  或许会
Um, a dad, maybe.
但罗德·天助不会
But not Rod Skyhook, yo!
史上最酷的新来转学生
The coolest new transfer student ever!
等等
Oh, wait.
现在的酷小孩一般怎么称呼女孩
What do cool kids call girls nowadays?
美人儿  美眉
Bettys? Shawties?
别担心  反正里面没有
Don't worry. There are none in there.
好
Okay.
什  什么
What, what?
真庆幸我的低血糖症
I'm glad my hypoglycemia
不会害我不准眼睛大吃糖心美人
doesn't prevent me from filling up on eye candy.
抱歉  我听不到你说话
Sorry. I can't hear you.
我在听物理系
I'm listening to a message
最性感教授的语音留言
from the sexiest professor in the physics department.
这么说吧  他去年一次研讨会上喝醉了
Let's just say he got drunk after a symposium last year
可是选了本小姐开车送他回家呢
and asked me to wheel him home.
感谢你邀请我来派对  兄弟
Thanks for inviting me to your party, brah!
音乐不错  小姑娘们都在哪呢
Sweet jams. Where are all the fillies at?!
-老爸  -老爸
- Dad? - Dad?
我是罗德·天助  刚来的转学生
I'm Rod Skyhook -- recent transfer student, yo!
那酷爆[牙啃]的声响从何而来
What's that knockin'?
是我  即将让这个派对炫酷起来
Oh, it's me, about to get this party rockin'!
天哪
Oh, God.
我的地界什么都是棒棒哒  小婊砸们
It's all good up under the hood, biznatches!
不出多久  这里的每个孩子
Pretty soon, every kid in here's
都会打电话给所有认识的人
gonna call everyone they know,
叫他们赶快过来
tell them to get their butts down here.
如果你想进一步增加人口流动量...
You want to gas up the foot traffic --
我是不会邀请家长们来的
I'm not inviting parents.
你的派对你说了算  兄弟
Your party, broseph!
不好意思  兄弟
Sorry, Jack.
给本舞王来点节奏
I'm gonna need some beats!
兰博
Rambo?
不  是特朗勃
No, Trumbo.
达尔顿·特朗勃  他在浴缸里写剧本
Dalton Trumbo. He wrote in the bathtub.
为什么
Why?
或许因为是个编剧
Maybe, as a screenwriter,
他知道编剧奖金肯定会大跳水[浴缸后侧洗澡]
he knew he was going to take a bath on the back end.
你一身鱼腥味
You smell like fish.
我的天  妹子们  这个派对太无聊了
Oh, my God, you guys. This party's such a snore.
我真不该离开卢克·邓菲的派对
I should have stayed at Luke Dunphy's party.
那边都疯得没边了
That was going off!
他不是那个为了一块钱
Isn't he the guy that ate
吃了一整罐蛋黄酱的家伙吗
a jar of mayonnaise for a dollar?
大概吧  因为他是个野性奇男子啊
Probably, 'cause he's a wild man.
所以他的派对总是那么疯狂
That's why his parties are always insane.
那派对可不是谁都能进去
Look, it's really exclusive,
但我大概能把你们加进邀请名单
but I could probably get you guys down on the list.
真的吗  都有谁在那
Really? Who's there?
受欢迎的都在  有卢克
Uh, just everyone. Luke...
还有罗德·天助
Rod Skyhook.
海莉·邓
Haley D!
格里芬
Griffin. Hey.
你怎么来我老妹的派对了
What are you doing at my sister's party?
没什么  帮我妈办点事
Oh, nothing. Just-Just something for my mom.
见到你真是太好了
Wow, it's so good to see you.
你还在做"销售"业吗
You, uh, still in the sales industry?
惭愧惭愧
Guilty.
有多惭愧  你这身囚衣是变装还是真的
How guilty? That is a costume, right?
是变装  我现在合法销售了
Yeah. I went legit.
我在药房工作  我送货
I work for a dispensary. I deliver.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我都忘了你有多讨人喜欢了
I forgot how much I like you.
你说的是小飞象吗
Did you say Dumbo?
不是  是特朗勃
No, Trumbo.
给你补充点背景知识
Little background.
在五十年代   威斯康星州某个
In the 1950s, a certain senator from Wisconsin
名叫乔·麦卡锡的参议员
named Joe McCarthy --
涨知识不如跳舞
Hey! Let's dance!
好吧
Oh, okay.
妈
Mom?
你说你会去卢克家的
You said that you were going to Luke's.
是的  可是杰说
Yeah, but Jay said --
你休想再狡辩  年轻人
Don't you say a word, mister!
我晚点再处理你
I will deal with you later.
杰说只要我往厄尔的鞋里放死鱼
Jay said I could come to the party
我就可以到这个派对来
if I put dead fish in Earl's shoes.
他这些瞎话都是怎么编出来的
Where does he come up with this stuff?
你扮成救世主  居然还敢说谎
Are you lying, dressed as our Lord and Savior?
那是什么  是你刚偷来的吗
What is that? Did you steal that?
不是  我一整晚都随身带着呢
No. I've had this with me all night.
你又说谎
You're lying again!
曼尼  离他远点
Manny, don't stand next to him!
普里契特
Pritchett!
瞧瞧你干的好事
Look what you did!
你这是在干什么
What the hell do you think you're doing?
我们正要走人  厄尔
We're just leaving, Earl!
那张索尔照[灵魂]是我的
That Soul is mine.
-还回来  -等地狱冰封了再说吧
- Give it back! - When hell freezes over!
你过来  厄尔  你给我过来
Come here, Earl! Come here!
一旦他们不再为
As soon as they stop fighting
新找的这个什么破由头打架了
about whatever stupid new thing that they're fighting about,
我们就上车去卢克家
we're getting the car and we're going to Luke's.
我真的没心情去另一个派对了
I'm not really in the mood for another party.
我今晚也没心情侮辱上帝
Well, I wasn't in the mood to insult God tonight,
但《圣经》上还说要"听老公的话"
but the Bible also said, "Listen to your husband."
我对这事看得很认真  别跟我作对
I'm very tense about this, so don't fight me!
给我上车去
And get in the car.
容不下我
I won't fit in.
那就把浴缸放到车顶上
We'll take this bathtub and put it in the roof.
不  我是说那个派对容不下我的
No. I won't fit in at the party.
没人会懂我这变装的哏  妈
Nobody gets me, Mom,
我开始担心永远也不会有人懂我了
and I'm starting to worry nobody ever will.
你的同龄人不懂你又怎么样
Who cares that the kids your age don't get you?
那意味着你比他们都有趣多了
That means that you're more interesting than them.
那意味着你会结交
That means that you're gonna be hanging out around people
更有趣的人
that are more interesting.
你会拥有
You're gonna have a more inter-
更有趣的人生  是啊  我知道
Interesting life. Yes, I know.
我从五岁起就听你这么说了
I've been hearing this speech since I was 5.
什么时候才能成真啊
When's it gonna happen?
耶稣都对恶魔用锁头功了
Jesus has the devil in a headlock.
你还不觉得有趣吗
That's not interesting to you?
不
No!
这是我的
This is mine!
是我想出的柜"索"雪橇这个哏
I'm the one who came up with "Storeski End Hutch."
就像我想出"女医生药恩"这个哏一样
Just like I came up with the "Dr. Quinn Medicine Cabinet."
改自1993年电视剧《女医生奎恩》
你只会抄袭  我才是创新者
You were the hack! I was the visionary!
我看到自己的倒影  不禁自问
I saw my reflection and I asked myself --
如果是耶稣会怎么做
What would Jesus do?
我是时候做个更大度的人了
It's time to be the bigger man.
这事没完  普里契特
This isn't over, Pritchett.
我不想再和你争下去了
I don't want to do this anymore.
你什么意思
Wh-What are you saying?
已经争了太久了  所有的谎言与愤怒
This has gone on too long. The lies, the anger.
以及我今晚在你袜子抽屉里留下的东西
And what I left in your sock drawer tonight.
什么
What?
签名照你留着吧  厄尔  我宽恕你
Keep the picture, Earl. I forgive you.
这样肯定会吓疯那个老混账的
It's gonna drive that son of a bitch crazy.
海莉
Haley.
我都等了一小时了
I have been waiting for over an hour,
然而没有一个人离开这个派对
and not a single person has left this party.
我的天  这是我吃过最好吃的寿司
Oh, my God, this is the best sushi I've ever had.
我第一次能吃出海产的黄狮鱼味
For the first time, I can taste the yellowtail from the sea
和陆产的大米味
and then the rice from the land,
然后又回到海产的海苔味
then back to the sea for the seaweed.
我看你吃海草前还吸了点别的"草"
Looks like you did more than just seaweed.
妈  你太美了
Mom, you're beautiful.
老爸有没有时常夸你美
Does Dad tell you that enough?
如果你的头真的被菜刀砍了
I would hate to see a cleaver
-我会很伤心的  -别说了  宝贝
- in your head for real. - No. Honey.
-莎拉  -邓菲太太
- Sarah? - Mrs. Dunphy.
那是啤酒吗
Is that a beer?
不是我的  求你别告诉我爸妈
It's not mine. Please don't tell my parents.
这一刻我突然意识到
That's when I realized
我根本不需要海莉替我搞垮这个派对
I didn't need Haley to undermine a party.
我只需要释放一个"妈妈炸弹"
I just needed to drop the Mom-bomb.
你们俩别爽过头了
Don't you two look cozy.
别忘了  单亲妈妈养大一个孩子不容易的
Remember, it's not easy raising a baby by yourself.
快看呀
Oh, look at that!
酒精果冻的吃法可太有趣了
That's a fun way to serve Jell-O.
我得赶紧拍张照片给你们妈妈
Let me get a pic for your moms.
不好吗  别走啊
No? Come on!
好了好了
Okay. Ooh!
现在是不是好多了
Isn't that better?
这下我们终于可以看清楚和听清楚对方了
Now we can all see and hear each other.
不错吧
Nice, huh?
你脸上有点脏东西
You got a little something --
你是哪位  跑来我的派对上搞什么鬼啊
Who are you, and what are you doing at my party?
来确保大家有一个舒适  干净又"安全"的夜晚
Just making sure everybody's having a good, clean, safe time.
有人跟你们讲过关于疱疹的那些事了吧
Somebody's talked to you all about herpes, right?
我们还是去另一个小子的派对吧
Let's just go to that other kid's party.
我跟你说  我跟那个罗德·天助亲热过呢
You know, I made out with Rod Skyhook once.
他超迷我的
He's obsessed with me.
还记得上个星期我们一起吃午饭的时候
Hey, remember last week when we all had lunch together --
你点的是普通薯条  然后大爸帮你撒谎了
You ordered the regular fries and Daddy lied for you.
我去
Damn it.
慢着  他就在那
Wait. There he is.
黑武士  不许动
Darth Vader! Freeze!
好吧
Okay.
你好啊  朋友
Hey, there, fellas.
你看起来有点力不从心啊
You're a little old, aren't you?
你儿子  他拿鸡蛋扔了我
Your son -- He hit me with an egg.
我才没有  而且他还吼我了
No, I didn't! And he yelled at me.
慢着  慢着  你凶我儿子了吗
Whoa, whoa. You yelled at my son?
他抓了一大把糖还嘲讽大笑
He took a handful of candy and laughed.
他每年都这样
He does it every year.
所以呢
So?
所以
So...
你现在什么感觉
...how does it feel?
我感觉  你拿走了大概17分钱左右的糖
Well, it feels like you took about 17 cents worth of candy.
而我儿子也说没扔你鸡蛋  能完事了吗
He said he didn't egg you. Are we done here?
他骗人
He's lying.
我没有
No, I'm not.
好了  哥们  我不知道是谁拿鸡蛋扔了你
Look, buddy. I don't know who egged you,
不过我完全理解他为什么要扔你
but I can understand why.
小屁孩多抓了一点糖  你就追杀他到家
A kid takes a little extra candy and you chased him home?
他才9岁
He's 9.
你多大了  蝙蝠侠  50岁吗
How old are you, Batman? 50?
什么样人才能做出这么无聊的事啊
What kind of person does that?
我来  我来告诉你他是什么样的人
I will -- I will tell you what kind of person.
一个信仰文明社会的人
Someone who believes in a civilized society,
一个相信我们国家的未来就寄托在
who believes that the future of our country
我们现在怎么教育我们的孩子的人
depends on the lessons that we teach our children.
这位"什么样的人"
"What kind of person," Sir?
是一个英雄
A hero.
我真的没扔啊
I didn't do it!
得了吧  我们都听到你的笑声了
Oh, come on. We heard you laughing!
那是因为一个头上插着斧子的金发女人
'Cause the blonde lady with an axe in her head
冲你们扔了一个鸡蛋
threw an egg at you.
-金发女人  -斧子
- Blonde lady? - Axe?
那个喷水的整人花真是惹到我了
That squirting flower really yanked my chain.
此仇不报非君子
Could not go unanswered.
打中他也行了
Oh! Close enough.
谁干的
Who did that?!
他朝那边跑了
He went that way!
好吧  刚才确实挺丢脸的
Well, that was embarrassing.
不  不是这样的
No, it wasn't.
刚才你的表现很伟大
It was magnificent.
你为了我挺身而出
You stood up for me.
很多时候我都感觉是我一个人在对抗整个世界
Sometimes I just feel like it's me versus the entire world.
很高兴能知道我们两个人真的是
It's just nice to know that we really are a...
肝胆相照的强力二人组
a dynamic duo.
好了  吃糖后的崩溃来了[玩糖果爆破]
All right. Now we play candy crash.
好
Okay.
给我一点空间  小样儿
Give me some space, son.
爷就是这么拽着  废柴们
That's how we do, sucka!
这一切都只是我的想象
Is it just my imagination,
还是老爸真的挽救了你的蹩脚派对
or is Dad actually saving your lame party?
这一切都只是我的想象
Is it just my imagination,
还是你下巴上沾的真是罗本脸上的妆
or is Reuben's makeup on your chin?
我这是病  得治
I have a problem.
对不起
Oh! Sorry.
没事
Oh, okay.
实在很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
别这样说
Don't be.
这已经是今晚最接近有女孩跟我跳舞的一刻了
This is the most a girl's danced with me all night.
我喜欢你扮演的达尔顿·特朗勃
I love your Dalton Trumbo.
谢谢了  多罗茜·帕克小姐
Thank you, Dorothy Parker.
女诗人/作家  还是常相聚在阿冈昆酒店的
知名文字创作者小团体  "阿岗昆圆桌"创办人之一
你是今晚第一个猜到我这身打扮的人
You're the first person tonight who's actually gotten that.
你的感觉  我懂
I know how that feels.
超厉害的舞者在一楼大厅
Awesome rager on the ground floor!
二楼是禁止的不能去哟
Upstairs off-limits!
后院也不行  因为草皮刚刚翻新了
Backyard, too, 'cause it just got re-sodded!
哥们  玩得高兴吧
What's up, buddy?
典型的白痴高中生
Typical high-school idiot.
真是为这个国家感到担忧
I fear for this country.
我自信表示  现在场面嗨到一个
Well, I think it's safe to say that things here
恰如其分的地步
are appropriately out of control.
哎呀  妈呀
Oh, yeah -- Oh, wow.
我估计你租这套衣服的保证金是拿不回来了
And I think you might have lost your deposit on that thing.
你为什么都不跟我说我很漂亮这类的话了
How come you never tell me I'm beautiful anymore?
靠
Oh! Damn it.
你就让我来扔得了
Oh, just let me throw already.
美人  来我把水变成什么了[耶稣让水变酒]
Hey, gorgeous. Look what I turned this water into.
杰  够了  万圣节已经结束了
Jay, enough. Halloween is over.
来嘛  还早着呢  何不来过过万"生"节
Come on. The night is young. Why don't we go begat it on?
我是不会跟穿得像耶稣一样的人搞在一起的
I'm not going to fool around with someone dressed like Jesus.
歌洛莉亚  你这是在犯傻
Gloria, you're being silly.
是吗
Am I?
我曾经和一个叫叶苏的人恋爱
I once dated a guy named Jesus.
结果那年家里的庄稼都没有收成
There was no harvest that year.
是你叔叔喝醉了没放种子
Is that the same year your uncle got drunk
全种的玻璃球那年吗
and planted marbles?
那你觉得是谁驱使着他去做了这些事
Who do you think made him do that?
歌洛莉亚  恕我直言
Gloria, all due respect,
我觉得天上那位大兄弟有更重要的事情要处理
I think the big guy has better things to worry about
而不是两个性感的...  你知道
than two sexy, you know --
我先上楼去换一件稍微凡人一些的衣服
I'm gonna change into something a little more secular.